(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
世界がこんな風になって、どれくらい経っただろう。
How much time has passed since the world became like this?
どこまでも続く荒野、木々や植物に侵され崩れた建物、
Endless wastelands, buildings crumbling,
木々や植物に侵され崩れた建物、
overrun by trees and plants,
砂漠に埋もれ傾く巨大なビル群。
huge skyscrapers buried in the desert
and tilting over.
もうずっとずっと前に起きた災厄によって、
The world was destroyed by a disaster
世界は滅びてしまった。
that happened a long, long time ago.
そんな黄昏を迎えた世界で、
In this world facing its twilight,
あたしは失われた文明の遺物を
I make a living searching for
探すことを生業としている。
relics of lost civilizations.
浄水器や濾過器のような今でも使えるものから、
From things that can still be used,
like water purifiers or filters,
使い道のわからない箱のようなもの、
to boxes of unknown purpose,
朽ちかけた布などなど…。
rotting scraps of cloth, and so on...
そういったものを手に入れて、
Obtaining those things and
旅人として日々を過ごしながら、
living my days as a traveler,
ずっと探しているものがある。
there's something
I've been searching for all along.
それは遥か昔にこの世界から失われてしまった…
It's something that was lost from this world
「オンガク」というもの。
a long time ago... something called "music."
それが何かはわからない。
I don't know what that is.
どうして探そうとしているのかも、
I don't really know why
よくはわからない。
I'm trying to find it, either.
でも不思議とその響きに、惹かれるのだ。
But strangely, I'm drawn to its sound.
だからあたしは世界を旅している。
That's why I'm traveling the world.
答えを探して、彷徨っている。
Searching for answers, wandering about.
「オンガク」を見つけるために。
To find "music."
「オンガク」を見つけるために...
To find "music"...
さ、今日もがんばっていくかー
Well, let's do our best today too.
いっせーの！
Ready, set, go!
幾千の儚い鼓動
Thousands of fleeting heartbeats
惜しまずに 流れる時を
Passing by the time that flows without hesitation
追い越して 駆け抜ける世界
A world running through...
いくつもの名前と
Using several names and
いくつもの身体を
Several bodies,
遣い分けてうまく生きているけど
I live well by using them differently, but
胸の奥 痛いよ
It hurts deep in my chest
音立てて 軋むよ
It makes a sound and creaks
きっと、心、生命、ここにあるから
Surely, heart, life, because it's here
.EXE あたらしいあしたへ
.EXE To a new tomorrow
.EXE 今 漕ぎだす
.EXE Now I row out
.EXE 運命の波間にさらわれたくはない!!
.EXE I don't want to be swept away in the waves of fate!!
いっせーの！
Ready, set, go!
幾千の儚い鼓動
Thousands of fleeting heartbeats
惜しまずに 流れる時を
Passing by the time that flows without hesitation
追い越して 駆け抜ける世界
A world running through...
I pray monster
私はいつも祈ってる
I'm always praying
熱い思いをぶつけたら
If I throw my passionate feelings
奇跡さえ起こせるから
Because I can even make miracles happen
この景色すべては
All this scenery
淋しさでできてる
Is made of loneliness
願うだけですぐにそばにいられた
I could be by your side just by wishing
あの頃の姿を
The appearance of those days
追い求め彷徨う
Seeking and wandering
きっと火花、言葉、ここにあるから
Surely sparks, words, are here
.EXE なつかしい歌声
.EXE A nostalgic singing voice
.EXE 今 聞こえる
.EXE I can hear it now
.EXE シグナルの中でも受け取れるのはなぜ？
.EXE Why can I receive it even in the signals?
通じあう その喜びを感じたい
I want to feel the joy of connecting with each other
場所も時間も飛び越えて
Crossing over place and time
分けあえる世界
A world we can share
信じあう 音がすべてと悟ったよ
I realized that believing and sound is everything
君をもう一度見つけたら
If I find you once more
涙さえ輝くから
Because even tears will shine
I pray monster
いっせーの！
Ready, set, go!
幾千の儚い鼓動
Thousands of fleeting heartbeats
惜しまずに 流れる時を
Passing by the time that flows without hesitation
追い越して 駆け抜ける世界
A world running through...
通じあう その喜びを感じたい
I want to feel the joy of connecting with each other
場所も時間も飛び越えて
Crossing over place and time
分けあえる世界
A world we can share
信じあう 音がすべてと悟ったよ
I realized that believing and sound is everything
君をもう一度見つけたら
If I find you once more
涙さえ輝くから
Because even tears will shine
もうこの世界には、人はあまり残っていない
In this world, not many people are left anymore.
（文明が崩壊して、インフラも何もかもなくなってしまったのだから、仕方ないことだと思う）
(Since civilization collapsed and everything else is gone, I think it's inevitable.)
（だけど旅をしていると、時おり引き寄せられるような...）
(But while traveling, sometimes I'm drawn to...)
旅をしていると、何かに引き寄せられるように、誰かと出会うことがある。
While traveling, sometimes you meet someone, as if drawn to them by something.
こんなふうに。
Like this.
こんにちは。
Hello.
こんにちは。あなたは？
Hello. And who are you?
私はAZKi。
I'm AZKi.
この世界の地図を作りながら色々なところを調査する「開拓者」をしているわ。
I'm a 'Pioneer,' surveying various places while creating a map of this world.
君は？
And you?
あたしは旅をしてるんだ。
I'm on a journey.
なくなってしまった大切なものを探すために。
To find something precious that has been lost.
大切なもの？
Something precious?
うん。
Yes.
…「音楽」を。
... 'Music.'
ふーん。
I see.
そう、この世界線ではそうなのね。
So that's how it is in this timeline.
でもあなたは覚えているはずだわ。
But you should remember.
ん？
Hm?
記憶にはなくても、
Even if it's not in your memories,
胸の奥の深いところに、
deep within your heart,
一緒に過ごした時間…
the time we spent together...
気持ちを一つにした瞬間を。
the moments our feelings became one.
だってあなたにとってそれは……
Because to you, that...
とても大事なものだったはずだから。
must have been something very important.
完全少女論
Complete Girl Theory
作詞・作曲：北澤伸一郎
Lyrics/Composition: Shinichiro Kitazawa
あー　君が好きな服
Ah, those clothes you like...
濡れたまま残念
It's a shame they're still wet
こんな夜だから
Because it's a night like this
響かせてミュージック
Let the music ring out
お気に入りの歌は
My favorite song...
君は知らない
You don't know it
君だけ知らない
Only you don't know
感情論を　君に投げつけて
Throwing my emotional arguments at you
傷ついたふりしてるけど
I'm acting like I'm hurt, but
完全論争　いつも痛いくらい
Complete controversy, it always hurts
もっと確かめてみる
I'll try checking it more
全然論外　だけど涙出る
Totally out of the question, but tears fall
見ないでよ　ひどい顔なの
Don't look, I have a terrible face
単純だって　言われたくないよ
I don't want to be told it was simple
もっと確かめてみて
Try checking it more
ねえ　朝が来る前に
Hey, before morning comes
連れ出してみて
Take me out
こんな夜だから
Because it's a night like this
鳴り止まないミュージック
Music that won't stop ringing
お気に入りの曲は
My favorite song...
君は踊らない
You won't dance to it
君だけ踊らない
Only you won't dance
感情論で　君を傷つけて
Hurting you with my emotional arguments
こんなひと　嫌になるでしょう
You'll grow to hate someone like this, right?
純情なんて　呆れるくらいに
Amazing how pure my feelings are
ほんと似合わないけど
They really don't suit me, though
テンションちょっと　上げて知らんぷり
Raising the tension and feigning ignorance
困らせたい　そんな気分よ
I feel like making things difficult
単純だって　言われたくないよ
I don't want to be told it was simple
きっと我儘だけど
I'm sure it's selfish, but
完全少女論
Complete girl theory
自分中心度
Degree of self-centeredness
気分上々層
Layer of high spirits
いいじゃんこれで
This is fine
未然純情論
Unforeseen pure theory
美学絶頂層
Peak of aesthetic
異常気象でしょ
It's abnormal weather, isn't it?
ほんのちょっと　手を伸ばして
Just reaching out a little bit
きっと全然　気づかない
I'm sure you won't notice at all
笑うよ　朝が来たら
I'll laugh when morning comes
だいじょうぶ
It's okay
だから感情論を　君に投げつけて
So, throwing my emotional arguments at you
演じてるふりしてるけど
I'm acting like I'm performing, but
完全想像　いつも痛いくらい
Complete imagination, it always hurts
君は優しいけれど
You are kind, but...
感情論を　君に投げつけて
Throwing my emotional arguments at you
傷ついたふりしてるけど
I'm acting like I'm hurt, but
完全論争　いつも痛いくらい
Complete controversy, it always hurts
もっと確かめてみる
I'll try checking it more
(さっきのは...... なんだったんだろう)
(What... was that just now?)
(たくさんの人たちと、熱気に包まれて、私はすごくワクワクしてた)
(Surrounded by so many people and the heat, I was so excited.)
(別だかすごく懐かしい感じがした......)
(It felt strangely nostalgic...)
ねえねえ、キミ、大丈夫？
Hey, hey, are you okay?
え？
Eh?
なんか顔色が良くなかったからさ。
Because you didn't look very well.
あ、うちはミオだよ。占い師をやってる。
Ah, I'm Mio. I'm a fortune teller.
お、キミ、何かを探してるね。そう占に出てる。
Oh, you're looking for something. It says so in your fortune.
わかるの？
You can tell?
うん。よかったら話してみて。何か力になれるかもしれないし。
Yeah. If you'd like, try talking to me. I might be able to help.
実は......
Actually...
なるほど...... キミは『オンガク』を探してるんだね。
I see... You're looking for 'Music'.
それなら、あそこに行ってみればいいんじゃない？
In that case, why don't you try going there?
世界の果てにあるっていう、光の塔。
The Tower of Light, said to be at the end of the world.
そこには天使が住んでて、人の願いを叶えてくれるんだって。
They say an angel lives there and grants people's wishes.
そこに行ってお願いをすれば、探し物も見つかるんじゃないかな？
If you go there and make a wish, maybe you'll find it.
親切にありがとう。そこに行ってみることにするよ！
Thank you for your kindness. I'll try going there!
どういたしまして。でもお礼なんていらないって。
You're welcome. But like I said, I don't need any thanks.
ん？
Hm?
だってうちは...... キミのことが大好きだから！
Because I... I love you!
ずっとずっと前からね！
Since a long, long time ago!
遥か
Far away...
遠く
...so far.
続く
Continuing on...
果てなき道
...this endless road.
それでも　いつか
Still, someday...
辿り
...I'll arrive...
着くと信じて
...so I believe.
たとえ　今は
Even if, for now...
辛く
...it's painful...
厳しくても
...and harsh.
小さな
A tiny...
笑顔
...smile.
守る
I'll protect it...
全て捧げて
...giving everything.
心
Hearts...
重なる
...overlapping.
言葉より強い絆に
In a bond stronger than words.
染め上げていく
Staining it all...
ひとつになる鼓動で
...with a heartbeat that becomes one.
記憶
Tracing...
辿る
...memories.
追憶の
A journey...
旅
...of reminiscence.
続けて
Continuing on...
あらゆる
Taking...
ことを
...everything...
受け止めるから
...because I'll accept it.
言葉はいらないの
Words are not needed.
それは永遠に
That is, for all eternity.
いつも
Always...
近く
...nearby.
そばで
I was watching...
見ていたけど
...by your side, but...
気付かず
...even if...
いても
...I didn't notice.
今は　遠く感じる
Now it feels far away.
あとを
Chasing...
追いかけ
...after you.
絆から愛に変われば
If a bond turns into love.
染め上げていく
Staining it all...
二人だけの秘密
...a secret for just the two of us.
想いを込めた　言葉の強さ
The strength of words filled with feelings.
信じて
Believe in it.
…いてる
...listening
うちに秘めたとき
When I kept it inside,
覚悟していた
I was prepared.
未来をつむぐために
In order to spin the future.
気が付けばほら
Before I knew it, look,
心に宿る
it dwells in my heart,
灯火
the flame.
小さな光
If small lights
寄り添いあえば
nestle together,
そう 未来を指して
yes, pointing towards the future.
青く広がる あの渡る空
The blue sky spreading out, that sky we cross,
見上げる
I look up.
もう言葉すら いらないから
Because I don't even need words anymore,
ただ 抱きしめていて
just keep holding on.
時は永遠に
Time is forever.
降り注ぐ雨のような歓声。
Cheers like falling rain.
その中で、煌びやかな服を着たあたしは、
In the middle of it, wearing glamorous clothes,
幸せそうな笑顔で手を振っている。
I wave with a happy smile.
まるでもう一人のあたしのように。
As if it were another me.
世界の果てにあるという光の塔。
The Tower of Light, said to be at the edge of the world.
「音楽」を探すために、あたしはそこを目指すことに決めた。
To find 'music,' I decided to head there.
何日かかるかわからないけど、幸いなことに時間はたくさんある。
I don't know how many days it will take, but fortunately, I have plenty of time.
ただ……
However...
お腹、空いた……
I'm hungry...
あ、なんでわためを見てお腹を鳴らしてるの!?
Ah, why are you growling your stomach looking at Watame!?
え、わかんないけど、なんか君を見たら急に。
Eh, I don't know, but looking at you just made me feel it suddenly.
わためは「非常食」じゃないよ〜！
Watame isn't 'emergency food'!
見逃してくれたら、かわりにわためが歌うから〜
If you let me go, I'll sing for you instead~
歌……？
Song...?
歌って……なに？
Singing... what is that?
え、君、歌を知らないの？
Eh, you don't know about singing?
よし、じゃあわためが教えてあげるよ。
Alright, then Watame will teach you.
歌っていうのはね……
Singing is, you see...
滅びてゆくこのステラ
This Stella that is perishing,
絆をたどるストーリー
a story tracing our bonds.
受け継ぐ思いが
May the inherited feelings...
生まれ変われますように
...be reborn.
目の前
Before my eyes,
現れた無表情は
the expressionless face that appeared
誰にも 懐を見せないまま
without showing its true self to anyone.
事象が
The phenomenon
世界を歪ませて
distorts the world,
光が ただ眩しすぎた
and the light was just too dazzling.
燦々と照り付ける
Shining brilliantly,
荒野に残した足跡
the footprints left in the wasteland.
与えられたのなら 守るものだけ
If it was given to me, then only the things I protect...
滅びてゆくこのステラ
This Stella that is perishing,
叶うことがないとしても
even if it can never come true.
変えよう 世界を
Let's change the world,
灯してゆく
lighting it up.
震える手が弾いた
The trembling hand played,
意味を持たない銃口を
a meaningless muzzle.
輝く星の下
Under the shining stars,
私は今 息をする
I am breathing now.
それなら
If that's the case,
あなたは騙したんだ
then you deceived me.
forever has gone,
today is infinity
and yesterday's dreams,
today a faint memory (Ah)
forever has gone,
today is infinity
it's time to move on,
two eyes in the face of billions of voices
I saw the flashing lights move further in the distance
(dream was not meant to be)
and outside these walls that I have created
歪んだ鏡に 映る自分さえ
Even my own reflection in the distorted mirror
誰だか分からずに 問いかけ続けてた
I kept asking, not knowing who it was
崩壊してゆく 記憶の狭間で
In the threshold of memories that are crumbling away
真実の姿を 探し求めていた
I was searching for my true self
不確かなものばかりの この世界で
In this world full of uncertain things
確かなものを ひとつ見つけたから
I found one certain thing
もう迷わない 振り返りはしない
I won't hesitate anymore, I won't look back
明日へと続く道を 歩き出すよ
I'll start walking the path that continues to tomorrow
forever has gone,
today is infinity
and yesterday's dreams,
today a faint memory (Ah)
forever has gone,
today is infinity
it's time to move on,
break it down
check it out, check it out
加速するこの鼓動
This accelerating heartbeat,
止められない衝動
this unstoppable urge
境界線を超えて
Crossing the boundary line
未知なる領域へ
into the unknown territory
瞬きさえも
A time where even
許されない時間
blinking is not allowed
運命の鍵は
The key to destiny
すでにこの手に
is already in my hands
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
改めまして、獅白ぼたんです！
Once again, I'm Shishiro Botan!
今日は私の誕生日ライブに来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live today!
1曲目は「breath of stella」、そして2曲目は「Disintegration」をお届けしました。
The first song was "breath of stella", and the second was "Disintegration".
Disintegrationはね、昔から大好きな曲で、いつかライブで歌いたいなと思ってたので、
Disintegration is a song I've loved for a long time, and I've always wanted to sing it live,
今日こうして披露できて嬉しいです！
so I'm happy to be able to perform it like this today!
わためぇと一緒に歌った「breath of stella」も最高だったよね！
"breath of stella" which I sang with Watame was also great, wasn't it!
3D LIVEということで、色んな演出もこだわってみたんですけど、どうかな？
Since it's a 3D LIVE, I also put a lot of thought into various effects, how do you like it?
この背景の崩壊した街とかも、曲の雰囲気に合わせて作ってもらいました。
The background of the collapsed city was also made to match the atmosphere of the song.
そして！今日はゲストにわためぇが来てくれましたけど、この後も素敵なゲストが登場するかも...？
And! Watame came as a guest today, but there might be more wonderful guests appearing later...?
最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね！
Please enjoy until the end!
それでは、続いての曲にいきたいと思います。
Now then, I'd like to move on to the next song.
聴いてください、「Lioness' Pride」。
Please listen, "Lioness' Pride".
誰もいない 荒野を独り
Alone in a desolate wasteland,
風を受けて 走り続ける
I keep running with the wind
迷いなんてない この場所で
There's no hesitation in this place
叫び続ける my pride
I keep shouting my pride
the sound of stars colliding
echoes in the distance
and dreams they shatter
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow
stronger from the memories...
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow
stronger from the memories...
renew... the light...
the dream...
forever has gone,
today is infinity
and yesterday's dreams,
today a faint memory (Ah)
forever has gone,
today is infinity
it's time to move on,
(time to move on)
forever has gone
(it's time to move)
(time to move on)
It's time to move
(it's time to move)
and outside these walls that I have created
the sound of stars colliding
echoes in the distance
and dreams they shatter
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow
stronger from the memories...
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow
stronger from the memories...
renew... the light...
the dream...
forever has gone,
today is infinity
and yesterday's dreams,
today a faint memory (Ah)
forever has gone,
today is infinity
it's time to move on,
forever has gone
(time to move on)
(it's time to move)
it's time to move
「ウタ」を知ってから、数日が経った
A few days have passed since I learned of "Song."
旅路は進み、ようやく
The journey continues, and at last...
光の塔がおぼろげながらに見えてくる
...the Tower of Light comes into faint view.
だけど「オンガク」や「ウタ」について
But as for "Music" and "Song,"
知っている人は、ほとんどいなかった
there were almost no people who knew.
もしかしたらあたしは、ないものねだりをしているだけなのかもしれない
Perhaps I'm just asking for the impossible.
でも……新しい出会いはあった
But... there was a new encounter.
Ciaoooo! I'm Raora Panthera!
あたし、絵描きをやってるんだ！
I'm a painter!
きみを見たとき、ビビビッときたの！
When I saw you, I felt a spark!
きみにはこれが似合いそう！
This would look good on you!
さらさらさら……っと
Sarasarasara...
はい、プレゼント！
Here, a gift!
はい！プレゼント！
Here! A present!
これ……あたし？
Is this... me?
うん、「ステージ衣装を着た、キミの絵！So cute……」
Yeah, 'A drawing of you in a stage outfit! So cute...'
ちょ、ちょっとあたしには可愛すぎない？
Hey, isn't it a bit too cute for me?
そんなことないよー！すっごくぴったり！
That's not true! It fits you perfectly!
そ、そうかな……？
I-is that so...?
きみはこの「ステージ衣装」を着て……
You'll wear this stage outfit and...
Let's sing with me!!
YEAH~
The knacks of surviving in this world
are being human and being right
Everyone keeps telling me to grow up fast
And it is so tough, can't wrap my head around it
Your unfair rules
Ego trip into a loop
We do belong nowhere in this world
Yet we are surviving
Getting through anything
Stay alive
Hated ones Naked hearts
Worthless games that never end
Found them in the darkness in the end
何が正しくて 何が間違っているんだ
What is right and what is wrong?
僕はただ、
I just...
ここで生きてると 叫びたいだけ
want to shout that I'm alive right here.
I heard voices calling out my true name
I will never give up
or be swayed anymore
Nobody can stop me
This is the way I am
I'll execute you, drop dead baby
YEAH~
Everyone wanna choose the right path only
They would seek salvation in this closed world
Filthy hands and mind never get clean again though
And it is so tough, can't wrap my head around it
Cannot turn the clock back
Cannot take a turn back
We do belong nowhere in this world
Yet we are surviving
Getting through anything
Stay alive
Missing piece Warmth of hands
Joys and even stabbing pains
Found them in the darkness in the end
何が正しくて 何が間違っているんだ
What is right and what is wrong?
誰だって、
Even though everyone
ここで生きてると 叫んでいるのに
is shouting that they're alive right here.
Facing what they really want to do,
They'll make it at the cost of everything
Nobody can stop me
This is the way I am
I'll execute you, drop dead baby
YEAH~
また失って、もう嫌になって
Losing again, getting tired of it,
それでも消えなくて
yet it still won't fade away.
その心の名をなんと言うのだろう
I wonder what you call that feeling in your heart.
僕はここで今、叫んでいるんだよ
I am shouting here right now.
君だって、ここで同じように叫んでいるんだろう
And you must be shouting here in the same way too.
I heard voices calling out my true name
I will never give up
or be swayed anymore
Nobody can stop me
This is the way I am
I'll execute you, drop dead baby
YEAH~
So, this is the way I am
（色とりどりのわかいいらしい『衣装』）
(A colorful and cute "outfit")
（それは不思議とぴったりと身体に馴染んでいた）
(It fit my body perfectly and mysteriously)
（『衣装』を身にまとい、『ヘッドセット』をつけて、『歌う』あたし）
(Wearing the "outfit," putting on the "headset," and "singing," that's me)
（あっちのあたしと、今のあたし、どっちが本物なんだろう）
(That me over there and the me right now, I wonder which one is real?)
そういう時はね、難しいことを忘れてぱーっと楽しいことをするに限るかな？
In times like that, it's best to forget the difficult things and just have fun, I guess?
クレープを焼いたりとか、アロマで癒されたりとか、
Like baking crepes, or being healed by aromas,
ベリーダンス踊ったりとかして気持ちよくなれば、悩み事なんてどこかに飛んでいっちゃうものなんだよ
If you do things like belly dancing and feel good, your worries will just fly away somewhere.
そういうものなの？
Is that how it is?
うん、そういうものかな〜
Yeah, I guess so~
だって世の中のだいたいのことは、それがどう見えるかなっていうのは、見る人次第なんだから
Because for most things in this world, how they look depends on the person seeing them.
たとえばアキロゼのこの格好が、芸術的に見えるかセクシーに見えるかは、あなたたち次第、みたいにね
For example, whether Akirose's outfit looks artistic or sexy depends on you all, like that.
え、あ、うん
Ah... uh... yeah.
そうだ、せっかくこうして出会えたんだから、一緒に踊ろっか？
That's right, since we've finally met, why don't we dance together?
あなたとアキロゼの二人で
Just the two of us, you and Akirose.
え、でもあたし、踊ったことなんてないんだけど
Eh, but I've never danced before.
大丈夫大丈夫。これはあなたのためだけに考えた、踊り子アキロゼの振り付けだから
It'll be fine, it'll be fine. This is a choreography for dancer Akirose that I thought of just for you.
ね？
Right?
とある竜の恋の歌
The Song of a Dragon's Love
音のない第一の大地に
In the silent first land
恋の歌 響けば
If the song of love resounds
錆びた竜の歯車
The rusty gears of the dragon
埋められぬ定めが
The fate that cannot be sealed
弾けた
Burst open
蘇る
Reborn
今
Now
いにしえより近づく
Approaching from ancient times
轟く恋
Resounding love
目覚めた
Awakened
絆を 求めて
Seeking the bond
炎は 迸る
The flames gush out
破壊と 再生
Destruction and rebirth
気高き君の呪縛
The noble curse of you
透き通る魂
A transparent soul
嘘もなく気高く
Noble and without lies
限界も抱えて
Embracing even the limits
未熟な恋も問う
Asking even of immature love
愚かさ
Foolishness
月明かり 今
Moonlight now
二人 照らす月
The moon illuminating the two
泡沫の時
Ephemeral time
重ねた
Overlapped
絆の 行方を
The whereabouts of the bond
両手で 抱きしめた
Embraced with both hands
終わりと 始まり
The end and the beginning
尊き君の記憶
The precious memory of you
Draco in fabula
Dragon in a legend
In dracone hora
Time dwelling in the scales
In dracone spes
Hope entrusted to the scales
In dracone error
Doubt floating on the scales
In dracone veritas
Truth sleeping in the scales
In dracone somnium
Illusion shifting in the scales
In dracone fatum
Destiny reflected in the scales
In dracone causa
The reason hidden in the scales
絆を
Seeking...
求めて
...bonds
炎は
The flames...
ほとばしる
...surge
破壊と
Destruction and...
再生
...rebirth
気高き君の呪縛
The spell of your noble self
絆の
Of bonds...
行く末を
...the future
両手で抱きしめた
I embraced with both hands
終わりと始まり
The end and the beginning
遠い君の記憶
A distant memory of you
どこか懐かしいだれかと出会う度に、頭に浮かぶ映像が鮮明になってくる
Every time I meet someone nostalgic, the images in my head become clearer.
もう少しで……何かがわかりそうな気がした
I felt like... I was just a little bit away from understanding something.
それって、ライブなんじゃないかな？
Isn't that... a 'live'?
ライブ？
A live?
うん。私、旅芸人だから噂で聞いたことがあるんだけど。音楽があった頃には、よく開催されてたんだって
Yeah. See, I'm a traveling performer, so I've heard rumors. They used to be held often back when music still existed.
ふーん。
Hmm.
そうだ。あたしはライブをやっていたんだ……
That's right. I was doing lives...
ねえ、気になるなら今からここで、私と一緒にやってみる？
Hey, if you're curious, why don't you try doing one here with me right now?
え？
Eh?
っていうかやろうよ！ あなたとならやってみたい！
I mean, let's do it! I want to try it with you!
「ライブ」ってやつを！
This 'live' thing!
なにを求めるのか
What are you seeking?
誰を愛するのかさえ
Even whom you love...
わからず
...I don't know
灰のように朽ちていく心に
In a heart decaying like ash
あなたのかけらだけは
Only fragments of you...
手探りでも
...even if groping in the dark
かたちをなぞれば
...if I trace the shape
長い眠りの中
In a long sleep
あなたを夢見るでしょう
I dream of you
ふたり見慣れた
The days we were accustomed to...
あの日々を何度でも
...together, again and again
夜明けはあなたにだけ
Dawn belongs only to you
空にはもう果てがないから
In the sky, there is no longer any end
なにを求めたのか
What was I seeking?
遠い日のわたしに今
To the me of long ago...
問いかけ
...I ask
砕かれ色褪せ落ちていく
Being crushed, fading, and falling...
あの
That...
かけらたちはどこへ
Where are those fragments?
Into Gray
手探りでも かたちをなぞった
Even if fumbling, I traced the shape.
長い夢の中で いま
Now, within a long dream...
あなたと
With you,
また出会えた
I could meet again.
ふたり 願った この瞬間を 最後まで
This moment we both wished for, until the end.
ひろがる 青い空が
The spreading blue sky...
あなたを
will always...
いつでも見てるから
be watching over you.
光の塔はもう目の前に迫っていた
The Tower of Light was already closing in.
それにつれて、頭に浮かぶ映像はさらに鮮明になってきていた
As it did, the images in my mind became clearer.
まるで夢から醒めるように
As if waking from a dream,
まるでそれが本物であるかのように
as if it were real...
──『ライブ』をしていた場所が
—the place where we held the 'Live'.
……着いた
...I've arrived.
ここが……光の塔
So this is... the Tower of Light.
塔っていうよりも、何かの舞台みたいにも見えるな
It looks more like a stage than a tower.
似てる……気がする
It feels... similar.
あの、『ライブ』をやっていた場所に
To that place where we held the 'Live'.
いらっしゃい、ライオンさん
Welcome, Mr. Lion.
キミが……願いを叶えてくれる “天使”？
Are you the 'Angel' who will grant my wish?
うん、そう. キミが来るのを待ってたよ
Yes, that's right. I've been waiting for you.
この世界に……『オンガク』を取り戻すことができるキミを
For you, who can bring back 'Music' to this world.
『オンガク』を？ あたしが……？
'Music'? Me...?
そうだよ
That's right.
ここに来るまでにたくさんのものを受け取ったキミは
After everything you've received on your way here,
もう『オンガク』が何か分かってるんじゃないかな？
don't you already know what 'Music' is?
ほら、ボクと一緒に飛ぼう
Come, let's fly together.
Asphodelus
囚われた絶望の淵で
In this abyss of trapped despair,
わたしを抱きしめてください
please hold me.
静寂に埋め尽くされ 一人で凍えてる
Engulfed in silence, I am freezing alone.
崩れ堕ちてゆく楽園の果てで
At the end of this crumbling paradise,
忘れられた祈りが響いてる
the forgotten prayer is resounding.
支配する闇の中でも涸れない愛よ
Oh love that does not wither even in darkness,
目覚めよ 永久に
awaken, eternally.
無限に降る孤独を
This infinite loneliness...
その指で染めてください
please dye it with those fingers,
叫ぶこの心が
so that this screaming heart
悲しみを愛せるように
can love the sadness.
まだ見ぬあの光の景色へ
Towards that scenery of light yet to be seen...
…灯して
...light the way,
…てく
...forward.
滲む まぼろし
A blurred illusion.
宿命の 鐘を
The bell of destiny.
そのぬくもり 素肌に
That warmth on my skin,
伝うまで
until it reaches me.
ほとばしる 嵐の中も
Even in the gushing storm,
やまない 愛よ 目覚めよ
the love that never stops, awaken.
抗えぬ 願いを
This unresistable wish,
その手で 迎えてください
please receive it with those hands.
出逢えた 喜びに
In the joy of having met,
震えてる 裸の心で
with a trembling, naked heart,
求める あの 残酷の彼方へ
searching towards that cruel beyond.
こぼれ散る 涙が
Spilling tears,
キラキラと 風に舞う頃
sparkling as they dance in the wind.
絆を 痛みを 抱きしめ
Embracing the bond and the pain,
永遠に 消えないように
so they never disappear forever.
無限に 降る 孤独を
The loneliness that falls infinitely,
私に 預けてください
please entrust it to me.
呼び合えた 心が
The hearts that called to each other,
扉を 放ち 羽ばたく
opening the door and taking flight.
近づく あの 始まりの空へ
Approaching that sky of beginning.
数時間前、露天
A few hours ago, at the street stalls.
へー、この街の露天は品揃えがいいな。
Heh, the street stalls in this town have a good selection.
他では見ない珍しいものがいっぱいある。
There are lots of rare things I don't see elsewhere.
旅を続けてると、やっぱりどうしても装備品は必要になってくるからな……。
When you're traveling, equipment inevitably becomes necessary...
ちょっと覗いていこう。
Let's take a look.
あ、これいいな。「ブランケットインクッション」
Ah, this is nice. "Blanket in Cushion".
ブランケットなのに袋に収納すればクッションにもなるから、
Even though it's a blanket, it becomes a cushion when you put it in the bag,
これがあればどこでも一休みできて、旅のお供にぴったりかも。
so with this, I can take a break anywhere. It might be perfect for travel.
コンパクトなのにふかふかで、寝心地もよさそう。
It's compact but fluffy, and it looks comfortable to sleep on.
収納袋の絵もいい感じ。
The illustration on the storage bag is nice too.
こっちは何だろう？
What's this?
「SSRBミニウォレット」か……。
The "SSRB Mini Wallet", huh...
買い物をしたり、小物を収納するのに財布は必需品なんだよね。
A wallet is a necessity for shopping and storing small items.
小銭もお札も入れられるっていうのも嬉しいな。
I'm glad it can hold both coins and bills.
今使ってるのも古くなってきたし、そろそろ買い替えてもいいかも。
The one I'm using now is getting old, so maybe it's time for a replacement.
お、この「ブレスレット」、かっこいい。
Oh, this "bracelet" is cool.
デザインが馴染みやすいから普段使いしやすそうだし、ライオンの加護も付いてるんだー。
The design is easy to blend in, so it seems easy for daily use, and it even has the Lion's Protection.
これを付けてたら君もライオンになれるかも……？
If you wear this, maybe you can become a lion too...?
なーんて。
Just kidding.
ふふ、これ可愛いな。ヘルメット被ってる。
Hehe, this is cute. It's wearing a helmet.
「SSRBぬいぐるみキーホルダー」
"SSRB Stuffed Keychain"
付けてるだけですっごく楽しい気分になれそう。
Just having it on seems like it'll make me feel really happy.
手のひらサイズのちょうどいい大きさだから、バックパックにぶら下げてもいいし、
It's just the right size, palm-sized, so I could hang it on my backpack,
ベルトに付けるのとかもありかな。
or maybe attach it to my belt.
これも購入候補っと。
Putting this on the purchase candidate list too.
どうしよう、全部欲しい……。
What should I do? I want them all...
どれにするか迷う……。
I can't decide which one to get...
え、これを全部まとめたセットもあるんだ？
Eh, there's even a set that includes all of these?
しかもそれだと、収納袋の絵を描いてるトマリ先生の書き下ろしのポストカードと
And with that, you get a newly drawn postcard by Tomari-sensei, who did the storage bag illustration,
直筆サイン、箔押しメッセージ……が特典で付いてくるのか。
along with a handwritten signature and a foil-stamped message as bonuses.
ふむ。
Hmm.
……セットでください。
Give me the set, please.
あー……
Ah...
やっとわかった気がする。
I feel like I finally understand.
AZK、ミオ、わため……
AZKi, Mio, Watame...
ラオーラ、アキロゼ、リオーナ...
Raora, Akirose, Riona...
かなた... そしてこの舞台に向けて声援を送ってくれていたたくさんの皆。
Kanata... and everyone who sent their cheers to this stage.
みんなから受け取ったたくさんのもの... そこに込められた想い。
Everything I received from everyone... and the feelings within.
それらが連なって... 音楽になる。
They come together... and become music.
新しいあたしが生まれるんだ。
A new me is being born.
うん、君ならそう言ってくれると思った。
Yeah, I thought you'd say that.
そんな君に僕から... 僕たちから... 最後に曲を送るよ。
To that you, from me... from us... we'll send a final song.
今日という素敵な日の最後を飾る...
To crown the end of this wonderful day...
新しい獅白ぼたんの誕生を祝う 世界で一つだけの曲。
a song unique in the world to celebrate the birth of a new Shishiro Botan.
今の君なら歌えるはず。
You should be able to sing it now.
音楽を 取り戻せるはずだから。
Because you should be able to take back the music.
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
15分早起きした
I woke up 15 minutes early
奇跡的な起床記録
A miraculous record for waking up
珍しい誇らしい朝
A rare and proud morning
誰のせいでしょーか？
Whose fault is it?
きみのガオが聞こえると
When I hear your "Gaoh!"
気がするだけかもしれないけど
It might just be my imagination
無敵になる気がして
But I feel like I've become invincible
走って 走って 走れんだ
Running, running, I'm running
Shine on!
どこ？って迷っちゃっても
Where? Even if I'm lost
Ride on!
合図は遠くの声
The signal is the voice from afar
Ride on!
迎えに行くよ
I'm going to meet it
We're Lions!!
Shine on!
きみがいる世界が
The world where you are
Ride on!
輝く合言葉
The shining password is
がおっていいやつみんんで
"Gaotte" - good ones, everyone!
Everybody, say
1-2-3!!
1, 2, 3!
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
ひとりじゃないって魔法をかけたら
If you cast a spell saying "You're not alone"
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
不安にだって一緒に吠えて
Even if you're anxious, howl together
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
笑顔でバフかけちゃうから
Because I can cast a buff with a smile
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
ここがそう 私達の最高
This is, yes, our best
Rawr rawr!! Yeah!
一日一獅子 Motivation
1 day, 1 lion's motivation
低めのやる気が御出上昇
My "low" motivation is now "rising"
Join us my peeps! 百獣で優勝
Join us, my peeps! 110 for the win!
だからがおってきましょう
So let's gaotteko
靴擦れした右足が
My right foot that got un-shod
今日のやる気を持ってった
Held today's motivation
椅子の角っこ小指も
The corner of the chair and my pinky finger
ついでにしばいてくれた
Also bit it for me, on the way
きみのガオが聞こえると
When I hear your "Gaoh!"
そんな日もちょっと優しくなる
Even days like that become a little kinder
おすそわけしたくて
I want to share the "osuso-wake"
踊って 踊って 踊ってんだ
Dance, dance, dance!
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
ジャンプするなら今しかないし
If you're going to jump, there's only now!
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
高いトコ目指しちゃおうよ Let's go!
Let's aim for the high ground, Let's go!
Shine on!
この一瞬がプレゼント
This moment is a gift
なんて真顔じゃ言えない
I can't say that with a straight face
だから吠えちゃうの
So I'll just howl it
We're Lions!!
Shine on!
きみがいる毎日が
The days where you are
Ride on!
歌う合言葉
The password we sing
がおっていいやつみんんで
"Gaotte" - good ones, everyone!
Everybody, say
1-2-3!!
1, 2, 3!
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
小声でもSay ちゃんと聞こえてる
Even if it's a whisper, say it, I can hear you
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
じゃあ叫んだら未来に届く？
Then if I shout, will it reach the future?
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
みんなでなら446dB
Together, we're 446dB!
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
ここがそう 私達の最高
This is, yes, our best
Rawr rawr!! Yeah!
言葉にすると真っ直ぐすぎて
If I put it into words, it's too straight
くすぐったい胸の奥だから
It tickles deep in my chest
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
「ありがとう」のかわりを
In exchange for "thank you"
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
ここがそう 私達の最高
This is, yes, our best
これは... あたしが見てる夢？
Is this... a dream I'm having?
それともライブをしてるあたしの方が 夢のあたしが見てる...？
Or is the me performing the live the one the dream me is seeing...?
それとも、ライブをしてるあたしの方が、今のあたしが見てる夢...?
Or is it the 'me' performing the live that's the dream my current self is seeing...?
胡蝶の夢って知ってる？
Do you know of the Butterfly Dream?
君の言う通り、この世界はもしかしたらもう一人の君が見ている夢なのかもしれないし、
Just as you say, this world might be a dream that another version of you is seeing...
もしかしたらさっきまで君が見ていた「ライブ」こそがこの世界の君が見ている夢かもしれない。
...or perhaps the 'live' you were watching until just now is the dream that the you in this world is seeing.
もしかしたら、いつか訪れる未来なのかもしれないし、
Perhaps it's a future that will come someday...
観測された違う世界線を垣間見てるだけなのかもしれない。
...or maybe you're just catching a glimpse of a different observed timeline.
世界は不確定なんだよ。
The world is indeterminate.
「音楽」は、そんなたくさんの世界を繋ぐ糸みたいなもの。
Music is like a thread that connects all those many worlds.
数え切れないほど存在する可能性の中で、それでも音楽だけはいつだってそこにあるものなの。
Among the countless possibilities that exist, music is the one thing that will always be there.
うちたちが、ぼたんのことを思う気持ちもね。
Just like the way we all feel about you, Botan.
わため、どこにいてもぼたんちゃんのことが大好きだよ！
Watame will always love Botan-chan, no matter where she is!
ぼたん先輩の絵、また描きたいなー！
I want to draw Botan-senpai again!
ふふ、ししろと同じ時間をのんびり過ごすの、アキロゼはすっごく好きかなー。
Hehe, Akirose really loves spending relaxing time with Shishiro.
ぼたん先輩、いつかは私と一緒にまた歌ってほしいです！
Botan-senpai, I want you to sing with me again someday!
でも、その前に...
But before that...
せーの、誕生日おめでとう！
One, two... Happy Birthday!
みんな... ありがとう。
Everyone... Thank you.
みんなの気持ち、送ってくれたお祝いの言葉... 確かに受け取ったよ。
Your feelings, the congratulatory words you sent... I've certainly received them.
すごく... すごく、うれしい。
I'm very... very happy.
今ならきっと、前だけを見て走っていられる。
Right now, I'm sure I can keep running, looking only forward.
これからも新しい世界に、まだ見たことのないたくさんの可能性に、挑戦することができる！
From now on, I can challenge new worlds and the many possibilities I haven't seen yet!
だってここが... あたしたちの「最高」だから。
Because this is... our 'best'.
だから、この先も一緒に行こう！
So, let's keep going together from here on!
次に生まれるのが、どんな世界でも。
No matter what world is born next.
みんなのこと、本当に、本当に大好きだよ！
I really, really love you all!
次にあたしが生まれるのは、どこなんだろう
I wonder where I will be born next.
でもそれがどこでも大丈夫
But no matter where it is, it's okay.
さよならは言わない
I won't say goodbye.
きっとあたしはこの幸せな物語を胸に どこまでだって飛べるはずだから
Because I'm sure I can fly anywhere with this happy story in my heart.
そこに「音楽」と、みんなからもらった温かくて優しい思いがあれば！
As long as there's music and the warm, kind feelings I received from everyone!
次の世界で、また会おう――
Let's meet again in the next world—
君がいる世界で――！
In the world where you are—!
新しい世界に旅立つ？
Depart for a new world?
だって決めたんだ。それでも――何でも大好きだからって
Because I've decided. Even so—because I love everything.
えー、わためはまだまだそばに居てあげるから、
Eh, Watame will still be by your side,
きっと思い出になるよ...
so I'm sure it'll become a memory...
大丈夫。だってお互い、どこにいてもすぐ見つかるんだから！
It's okay. Because we'll find each other instantly, no matter where we are!
「一緒に頑張ろう」
"Let's do our best together."
また、いつか一緒にね
Let's be together again someday.
あたしがここにいるのは、みんなのおかげなんだよ
The reason I'm here is thanks to everyone.
うん、これからはその想いを持って進めば
Yeah, from now on, if you move forward with those feelings,
きっとまた会えるって信じてるよ
I believe we'll definitely meet again.
うん、あともうちょっとだけ！
Yeah, just a little bit more!
止まらない時計の針を
The hands of the clock that won't stop
追い越して
Overtake them
SHISHIRO BOTAN BIRTHDAY 3D LIVE
MUST RELIVE